It was a story where things finally came true, so I'm...
[とかかなったようなお話だったので、私もなんか、
...looking forward to looking back on it with you all. Please stick with me!
この後も振り返っていけたらなと思うのでよろしくお願いします。
Also, AfterTalk has undergone a bit of a mini-renewal.
え、そして、え、アフタートークがプチリニューアルいたしまして、
We've been collecting messages via the official ProSeka Discord and email.
事前にプロセカ公式ディスコートとメール
I remember performing with a heart full of...
すごく晴れやかで嬉しい気持ちを満載に演じさせていただい
...bright and happy feelings.
た記憶がございます。
It was a story where I really felt Shiho-chan's significance.
ね、そして志歩ちゃんの意味を感じたそんなストーリーだったなと思います。
Thank you all so much.
皆さんたくさんありがとうございます。
I'll be reading the letters we received during the show, so please look forward to it!
え、いただいたお頼りを番組内で紹介させていただきますので、是非是非お楽しみに。
Also, please post your thoughts on the event or this stream using the hashtag #ProSekaAfterTalk.
またイベントやこの放送の感想をハッシュタグプロセカアフタートークでポストしてください。
I'm also keeping an eye on the YouTube chat,
YouTubeのチャットも見ておりますので、
so I'll be picking out comments that catch my eye.
気になるコメントはどんどん拾っていきます。
I see lots of "Kon-needo" coming in!
こんにーどってたくさん来ておりますよ。
Thank you!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you for the comment saying you just finished reading the story.
さっき読み終わりましたって書き込んでいただいてありがとうございます。
Well then, let's get started right away.
じゃあ、じゃあ早速始めていきたいと思います。
I'd like to talk about the story for "Connecting with You: Heartbeat."
え、それでは早速今回の君と繋ぐハートビートのストーリーについてお話しできればと思います。
How did you all like it this time?
皆さん改めて今回いかがでしたでしょうかね。
I'd like to look back on it while reading your letters.
お頼りを紹介しながら振り返っていけたらなと思います。
First is a letter from Misora-san.
まずはみそらさんからのお頼りです。
From: Misora-san. "Noguchi-san, Kon-needo!"
野口さん、こんにーど。
Kon-needo!
こんにーど。
"Thank you for always providing such a wonderful voice."
いつも素敵な声をありがとうございます。
Thank you as well!
こちらこそありがとうございます。
While reading this event story,
え、今回のイベストを読んでいて、
the part where Ichika-chan put her strong feelings for Miku-chan into a song
いちかちゃんがミクちゃんへの強い思いを曲に込めるというところがすごく
was so moving and made me feel all warm and fuzzy.
感動アンドほっこりにこりしてしまいました。
I'm also really curious about Shiho-chan's meaningful look at the end.
え、ラストの志歩ちゃんの意味深な感じもすごく気になります。
Anyway, seeing Ichika-chan look so happy made me happy too.
何はともあれいちかちゃんが楽しそうでこちらも幸せになりましたとのことです。
Misora-san, thanks for the message!
みそらさん、感想ありがとうございます。
Right, this time Ichika wrote a song with the theme "What Miku means to me,"
ね、今回はその私にとってのミクっていうテーマでいちかが曲を作りまして、
and she created a song called "With" that's packed with
ミクといちかのこれまでを詰め込ん
everything about Miku and Ichika's journey so far.
だ楽曲Withっていうね、楽曲作ったんですけれども。
She uploaded it, then a creator named Aoi-san reached out to make an MV,
で、作ってアップして、そしたら葵さんっていうクリエイターの方から声かけてもらってMV作って、
and from there,
それがこう
it got so many views and started spreading in all sorts of ways.
すごく再生してもらって、いろんな広がりを見せていって
Like I said at the start, it was a story full of joy and happiness,
なんか本当最初も言いましたけどなんかこんなに幸せ
to the point where I wondered if it was okay to be this happy.
でいいのかなって思っちゃうような
It was such a heartwarming story,
なんか喜びとか嬉しさとかそういうのが詰まったストーリーでなんか嬉しかっ
and it made me really happy too.
たですね。
Ichika's goal of connecting people through music has already been achieved.
いちかのそのなんか目標としてる音楽で人と人繋いでいくっていうのがもう達成された。
Well, it's only the first step, but since it was a story where her wishes came true,
ま、まだ1本目だと思いますけど、このいちかが願ってたこととか叶ったようなお話だったので、
I remember performing the role
私もなんかすごく
with a very bright and joyful heart.
晴れやかで嬉しい気持ちを満載に演じさせていただいた記憶がございます。
And you mentioned being curious about Shiho-chan's meaningful look at the end.
ね、そして志歩ちゃんの意味深な感じもすごく気になりますって書いてくださってますけどどうですかね、
What do you all think?
皆さん。
How did it make you feel?
どう感じました?
Shiho ended by saying, "Ichika looks like she's having a lot of fun," but...
志歩は志歩は、あの、いちかすごく楽しそうだなっていう言葉を残して終わったんですけどま、
As for me...
なんか私として
Well, I guess it's true that there's a slightly uneasy feeling, but
は、ま、確かになってちょっとモヤッとする気持ちも、ま、
I don't think Shiho is feeling that uneasy yet.
志歩はまだそんなにモヤッとではないと思うんです
No, I think she's more like, 'What is this feeling?' That's what I think, but anyway,
よ。
for this AfterTalk, we were soliciting messages.
にてアフタートークへのお頼りを募集しておりました。
But amidst all that, Ichika was making songs with Miku-san all by herself, and
でもそんな中でいちかがこう、ま、1人でね、
I think she must have felt something from that experience.
ミクさんの曲を作ってっていうところで、ま、
Well,
何か感じることがあったんだろうなって思うんですけどま、
I have no idea what kind of story this will become from now on,
これ
but I'm looking forward to finding out. Hmm.
からどんなね、ストーリーになっていくのか私全然知らないんですけどうん。
Wow, is that what bands are like? I don't know.
わあ、バンドってそんな感じなのかな、わかんないけど。
But you know, there are so many people who make songs with Miku-san,
なんかでもほらミクさんで曲を作ってるけど、
but also play in their own bands, right?
自分でバンドもやってますっていう方たくさんいるじゃないです
So I hope Ichika can continue to do many happy things
だからいちかも、ま、そういう感じでいい感じに幸せなことを
in that same good way.
なんかたくさん続けていってほしいなって私は思う
So, I also want them to do their best as Leo/need, as a band,
のでま、でもやっぱレオニードとしてね、バンドとしても頑張ってほしいし、
and I want her to continue making music with Miku-san, whom she loves so much.
いちかの大好きなミクさんと曲作り
I don't know what will happen in the future, but I hope we can all watch over them
を続けてってほしいし今後どうなるかわかんないけどあたたかくあたかく見守っていけたらなと
warmly.
思っております。
Yes.
はい。
Well then, I'd like to introduce one more message.
では、では、もう1通お頼りを紹介したいと思います。
From: YMNK-san.
え、YMNKさんからのお頼りです。
Noguchi-san, i1Kon-needoi0.
野口さん、こんにーど。
i1Kon-needoi0.
こんにーど。
Uh, in this event story, Ichika created the song "With",
え、今回のイベントストーリーで自分自身とミクについての思いを込めた
pouring her feelings about herself and Miku into it.
1曲Withを作り上げたいちかです
There was a scene where, after finishing the song and having everyone listen, she already seemed satisfied.
完成してみんなに聴いてもらってすでにに満足していたようにも見えるワンシーンがありましたが、
Noguchi-san,
野口さんは
have you ever felt satisfied just by doing something, to the point where you didn't feel the need to do anything further?
このようにまるまるしたら満足してしまったみたいなことってありますか?
That's what they asked.
とのことです。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
You know, Saki-chan told her, 'Since you went to all that trouble, why not upload it?' and that's when she did.
ね、咲希ちゃんがこうせっかくならアップしたらって言ってくれてアップしたっていうところですけども。
Huh, something where I felt satisfied just by doing it?
え、まるまるしたら満足してしまったみたいなこと?
Hmm, let's see.
そうですね。
Recently, uh, I made curry.
最近、あの、カレーを作ったんです。
I suddenly wanted to make curry, and then I felt satisfied,
カレーを急に作りたくなってそしたら満足して
like, 'Eating it is too much trouble.'
食べるのめんどくさいなみたいな
I made several days' worth, you know.
何日か分作ったんですよ。
You know, everyone, I made several days' worth, but I just felt truly satisfied.
ね、皆さん、ね、何日か分作ったんですけどなんかこう満足しちゃったんです本当、
Exactly.
まさに。
I made it and felt satisfied, and then, I guess food I make myself isn't all that appealing, you know.
作って満足してで、やっぱなんかこう自分で作った料理ってそんななんか魅力的じゃないというか
I did eat it normally, but I guess it's like I felt satisfied just by cooking it.
食べたんですけどま、料理してしまったら満足してしまったっていう感じでございますかね。
And, this is totally unrelated, but, uh, I didn't have a kitchen knife at home.
で、なんか全然関係ないんですけど、あの、包丁がなくて家に
I didn't have one.
なかったんです。
I don't know why.
なんでかわかんない。
I had one, you know.
あったんですよ。
I had one, but the knife suddenly disappeared.
あったんだけど、急に消えて包丁が。
Isn't that scary?
怖くない?
So, I wanted to cut the carrots, but
で、人参を切りたかったんですけど
I couldn't, so I used scissors.
切れないからハサミで切って
And then I just went
もう
'snip, snip' and cut them. That's the story.
ってやって切ったっつう話です。
Yeah.
はい。
Were you satisfied with that?
それで満足したの?
Yes.
そう。
I put so much
力を
effort into making it that I was satisfied, and I didn't have the energy to eat it,
込めて作ったから満足しちゃって、食べる余力がね、
I guess.
なかったのかなって思いますけど。
You'd probably say, 'No way!'
そんなわけないだろっつってね。
Well, I did eat it later, so don't worry.
あの、後日食べましたが、はい、安心してください。
What was that story about?
何の話ですか?
Seriously.
本当に。
Thank you for the question.
ありがとうございます、質問いただいて。
Yeah.
はい。
Anyway, let's get back on track. This time too, I've picked out scenes I personally want to talk about,
ということで気を取り直して、え、今回も私が個人的に語りたいシーンをピックアップしましたので、
so let's watch them
一緒に見
together.
ていきましょう。
Now, please enjoy the video.
それでは動画、どうぞ。
Alright, this time I picked out Episode 8.
はい、今回は8話をピックアップさせていただきましたよ。
3 million...
300万
Isn't that amazing?
すごくないですか?
I think it means a lot of people listened to it smoothly, which is great.
すごく順調にいろんな人に聴いてもらったんだなって思いますけどね。
Really.
本当に
That's right.
そうですよね。
I feel like many people must have helped make this connection.
いろんな人がね、繋げてくださったんだろうなって思いますね。
Honestly, I didn't expect it to be this fast.
正直ここまで早いとは思ってなかったし。
I think so too.
私もそう思います。
I wonder if it'll be 5 million?
やっぱり500万かしら?
It'd be nice if we could reach that as a commemorative milestone.
記念費で迎えられるといいわね。
Yeah.
うん。
We should start listening together from around 4.95 million views.
495万回くらいから一緒に聴いてこなきゃ。
Waiting for 50,000 more sounds tough.
5万回待ちの大変そう。
It's great, even with KAITO-san's quiet comment, given the current momentum,
いいよね、このカイトさんのボソッとでも今の勢いなら
and that surprising second place, I wonder if that was a big factor.
ね、あの、まさかの2位っていうのでかかったかな。
Haruka-chan mentioned at the beginning that,
なんか事前に
you know, 'on the internet, it's being predicted like this, but...'
ネット上だとこうやって予想されてるけど、
Like, what's the actual ranking by feel?
なんか体感でどれくらいいかな順位みたいな。
They're watching it,
リアルと思って。
thinking it's real.
で、見てるんだよね。
Momojan also takes into account things like online vote counts and predictions,
ももちゃんもね、ネットの票数とか予想とかもさ。
using them as reference for their future productions.
で、そういうのも含めて自分たちの今後のプロデュースにその参考にしたりとか。
I thought it was really mature of them to gather all the hints they could get,
やっぱ得られるヒントは全部得て、
and then think about what to do next based on that.
その上でどうするかを考えられるっていうのがやっぱ大人だなって思ったし、
But they're high schoolers!
だって高校生だよ。
I don't think high schoolers could do something like that.
高校生がそんなことできないと思う。
Well then, thank you very much for all your messages.
ね、ということで、あの、メールたくさんありがとうございました。
Thank you too, Yukki-san.
ゆっきさんもありがとうございます。
Well, about the messages, there are only these two, but
あの、メールはね、も、この2通だけなんですけれども、
I have so much I want to talk about,
ちょっと私があまりにも語りたいので、
so please let me
ゆっくり語ら
take my time.
せてください。
You know,
あのね
the Lumina Grand Prix, for users,
ルミナグランプリって、あの、やっぱユーザーさん、
for ProSeka users, it felt like it took a really long time,
プロセカユーザーさんからするとものすごく、
didn't it?
長い時間かけ
They kept releasing it little by little, and you'd wonder
てた気がするじゃないですか。
when the preliminaries would finally end.
やっぱりちょっとずつ小出しにしていつになったら予選が終わるんだろう。
While there was a feeling of wanting to see the continuation quickly,
早く続きを見たいっていう気持ちもあればいや、
there was also a part of me that wished it would never end.
なんかもうこのまま一生終わんないでくれて思う自分もいて、
When I was right in that in-between state, at this timing when it finally went from preliminaries to finals,
なんかそのちょうど狭間ぐらいにいた時についに予選から決勝へっていうこのタイミングで
I was incredibly nervous.
めちゃくちゃ私は緊張してたんですよ。
And then, when I realized it was Haruka's banner, I thought, 'Wait,
それもしかもはるかのバナーだってわかった時に、ええ、
this story is going to be told from Haruka's perspective?'
はるか目線でこの物語が語られるんですか。
You know, especially in Haruka's case, as I'll talk about a bit later,
ね、特にはるかの場合は、この後もちょっとお話しするんですけど、
there's a clear wall, Hiiragi-san, and 'Rewrite',
柊さん、リライトっていう分かりやすい壁
isn't there?
があるじゃないですか。
That unavoidable presence.
あの、意識せざる負えない存在が。
She has to confront that again, you know.
なんかそこともう1回対峙するっていうね。
Last time, when she fought—well, 'fought' might be the wrong word—with Hiiragi-san,
あの、前回その柊さんと戦っ、戦ったっていう言い方あるですけど、あの、
when they confronted each other and talked one-on-one, it depicted a battle
対峙して1対1でね、お話しした時は、その、なんだろう
with an adult in the real industry, you know,
リアルな業界の中の大人との戦いみたいなのが
and Haruka's expression was very dark.
描かれていてで、はるかの表情もすごく暗くて、
So, it was a growth that happened while thinking,
だからなんかやばい、この壁乗り越えられないかもっていう中
'Oh no, I might not be able to overcome this wall.' That's why, this time,
での、その成長だったから、今回また改めてうわ、
I was reminded again, 'Wow, what kind of battle will Haruka have with Hiiragi next?'
柊さんと今度どんな戦いをするんだろう。
When that happened, I thought, 'Is the advice you get from a teammate,
ってなった時にあの、決勝前にして、リライトっていう
from Rewrite, right before the finals, really this reassuring?'
仲間、チームになった状態でもらえるアドヴァイスってこんなにも心強いのかと思いましたね。
When you have her on your side, that reassurance, that strength...
ちょっと味方につけた時の、あの、心強さ、力強さあの、もう圧倒的存在感と
...that overwhelming presence, and the feeling of security that 'everything will be fine if she's here'...
なんかこの人がいれば大丈夫って安心感ねが、
Every single word from Hiiragi-san conveyed all of that,
なんか柊さんの一言一言から全部伝わってきて、なんかここが多分
and I really felt that this is probably where Haruka respects her, where she wants to aim for,
はるかが尊敬してるところであり、目指したいって思う場所でもあり、
and also a big wall she has to overcome,
乗り越えなきゃいけないっていう大きな
I really felt that.
壁なんだろうなっていうのをすごく感じた
Was it episode 6?
6話かな。
I think it was around that time.
大体その辺だった気がする。
It's scary.
怖いんですよ。
The more reliable Hiiragi-san's presence becomes,
もう柊さんの存在がなんか
the more I simultaneously feel the threat of what's to come.
頼りになればなるほど、この先の脅威を同時に感じるっていう。
Right?
ね。
And so, I really wondered what kind of team Aslan was,
で、よりやっぱじゃあはるかが当時柊さんと一緒にやってたアスランって
the one Haruka was in with Hiiragi-san back then.
どんなチームだったんだろうっていうのがすごく気になるなって思いました。
Speaking of Haruka, it's Hiiragi-san, but looking at the whole picture,
で、はるかで言うとやっぱ柊さんなんですけど
other teams probably went to various places for events,
全体で見た時にやっぱ学習塾にイベントに行く
starting with cram schools, I think, you know,
なんか学習塾を始め他のチームもいろんなとこ行ったんだと思う
like, uh...
んだけどね、あの
Arisa-san's...
その有咲さんの
I thought about it.
考え
From the perspective of a former idol,
元アイドル
I felt like, 'I wanted to do this for them, but I can't now.
目線で見た時のこうしてあげたかった自分は今はできないけど、
I want to entrust that power to the new generation of idols.'
新しい今の子達にその力を持って託したいって
The idols in this SEKAI, their... what is it, their charisma?
思わせられるこの世界におけるアイドル達のなんだろう、人望?
It's just insane, I thought.
えぐいなと思って。
What was that?
何それ。
You guys, being entrusted by these legendary idols, you're truly amazing.
この伝説級のアイドルに任せてもらってる君達本当にすごいんだなって
I really felt that throughout the story.
ストーリーを通してすごく思いました。
Yeah.
うん。
Right.
そう。
It's good.
いいんですよ。
Right, you know, Kiriya isn't good, is he?
そう、あのね、霧谷は良くないですね。
I really love the line, 'You got me.'
当てられましたのセリフがすごく大好きで。
When I'm recording, I only get the script, of course.
私は収録の時に、あの、もちろん台本だけいただくわけです。
It's not like we're doing a back-and-forth exchange, so the finished product, you know,
駆け合いできてるわけじゃないので、完成したやつはね、
I play the game and hear it for the first time there,
私もプレイしてそこで初めて聞くんですけどもうシナリオ
but the scenario was already great, wasn't it?
から良かったもんね。
Oh, right, that scene with Arisa-san and Hiiragi-san.
あ、そうの有咲さんと柊さんのシーン。
That was just amazing.
あれはもうだめよ。
There's a part of me that played just to see that scene.
あれを見たくてやってたとこある。
This time around.
今回。
Of course, I wanted to see all of Momo-chan's scenes,
もちろんね、ももちゃんの全部のシーン見たかったですけど、
but I especially made sure to engrave that one into my memory
そこは特に絶対にもう焼き付けてやろうと思って
when I watched it.
見ました。
Right.
ね。
It seems like a change is coming, so the screen will go dark for a moment.
おお訪れがしているみたいなので、1回画面が暗くなります。
We'll be making adjustments, so please wait just a moment.
調整しますので、少々お待ちください。
I'll still keep talking, you know.
まだ語りますよ。
I guess I'll wait for the next comments to come in.
次のコメントが返ってくるのを待とうかな。
Can everyone hear me?
みんな聞こえてる?
Oh, you can hear me?
あ、聞こえた?
Okay.
オッケー。
I've confirmed that everyone's comments have come back,
みんなのコメントが戻ってきたのも、あの確認したので
so I'll continue.
語ります。
Right.
はい。
Ah, so, there are 8 episodes in total.
あ、えっとね、全部で8話。
I've been talking about Episode 6 this whole time, but let's talk about the other episodes too, okay?
で、さっきずっと6話の話をしちゃったんですけど、他の話の話もしましょうね。
The two-week 'Away Team Live'.
出張チームライブ2週間。
When I think about how the previous Lumina Grand Prixes were held over much shorter periods,
なんか今までのルミナグランプリがもっと短いスパンで行われてたんだっていうのを改めて感じると、
I realized what an amazing thing
すごいこと
they were doing.
やってるなって思いました。
You know, even before, they'd swap with other teams and shuffle songs and perform them,
ね、今までもあの、他のチームと入れ替えてさ曲シャッフルしてやったりとかってやってたけど、
but to think they did that every few days,
それを本当数
everyone's memory...
日のペースでやってたんだと思うと、みんなの記憶力、
Wow, my honest impression was, 'They're so young!'
うわ、若いなっていうのが素直な感想だったんだけど。
The speed is just incredible.
やっぱスピード感が
For active idols to learn songs... I mean, we heard that Minori
すごいなって、現役アイドル達のその曲を覚えるとかま、みのりが
is good at free-copying, but even other members still learn
そのフリーコピーが得意みたいな話は出てたけど
songs from other units. They memorize the songs,
なんかそうじゃないメンバーでもやっぱ他のユニットの曲を覚え
learn the dances, think about formations,
て、ま、曲を覚えて、ダンスを覚えて、フォーメーションを考えて、
and perform them originally, you know.
オリジナルでやって、みたいな。
And they also bring out their own strengths.
で、自分達の良さも出していく。
They have too much to think about, don't they?
考えること多すぎるでしょ。
They do it so well.
よくできてるよね。
I really want to learn from them.
マジで見習いたい。
It's truly amazing, isn't it?
本当にすごいよね。
And, you know, what I found most interesting and kept watching was
で、あの、私ちょっとさ、1番ちょっと面白くてずっと見ちゃったのが、
the comments.
あの、コメント。
Every time, the comments
毎回このももちゃんの
from viewers that appear
イベントのに出てくる
in Momojan's events...
の視聴者のコメント
Aren't those written by everyone?
あれ、みんな書いてない?
I think I've seen them before.
私見たことあると思うんだけど。
You know, I feel like there's a writer just for those comments.
ね、あの、コメント用の作家さんがいる気がする。
The accuracy is so high every time.
解像度高いよね、毎回。
I think there are a lot of people who feel like, 'Hey, I think I've tweeted this before.'
あれ、私これつぶやいたことある気がするって思ってる人いっぱいいると思うんだよね。
Hehe.
ふふ。
Busted.
バレた。
Oh, right, so either they're taking someone's comments, or they're
え、そう、だから誰かのコメントを取ってきてるか、それ用の方を呼んでいるか。
calling in someone specifically for that. They're always so real.
毎回リアルだよ。
It's really interesting, yeah.
本当に面白いなってうん。
I feel like that's one of the points that makes it feel real, you know?
なんかそこがやっぱリアルだなって思えるポイントの1個なの気もしますしね。
Yeah.
うん。
And every time, I'm a little curious about which comment in this story,
で、毎回ちょっと気になるもん、今回のストーリーの中で1番、
I'd probably say myself.
え、自分言いそうだなと思ったコメントあったって
You know?
ね。
Of course, sometimes they're lines of dialogue, but there are also descriptions of fans, right?
あの、もちろんセリフにもなってるけど、なってることもあるけどファンの描写もあるわけじゃないですか。
Like Momoka's fans, or...
だからももちゃんのファンとか、
Yeah, oh, right. It's a blessing that we don't hear that much anymore.
ね、あ、そう、今とはなってはあんまり聞かなくなったしがありがたいことですけどね。
It doesn't come up now, but back then, when people were like, "Who's Momoka?"
出なくなったけど、当時やっぱあの、ももちゃん知らないみたいな時にさ
Especially Minori,
特にみのりとか
and the other members were already doing their thing, at times like that, there were some really...
他のメンバーはもともとをしてたけど、みたいなタイミングとかにすごいね、あの、
rather harsh comments.
ちょっと辛辣なコメントが
Yeah, there were.
あったりとかもしましたし。
When you think about it, the current environment is so much better, isn't it?
そう考えると今のさ環境めちゃくちゃいいよね。
It makes me so happy that everyone says, "Oh, Momoka!"
みんなが、ええ、ももちゃんって言ってくれるのが本当に嬉しい。
Right.
そう。
It's gotten a lot kinder, hasn't it?
だいぶ優しくなったよね。
Or rather, it means Momoka has become
優しくなったっていうか、それだけやっぱももちゃんが
more widely known to everyone.
みんなに知られるようになったってところなんだろうね。
Like appearing on TV and stuff.
テレビで、出るようになったりとかさ。
Yeah.
うん。
I really think the power of comments is incredible.
コメントの力って本当にすごいと思うな。
It's all about effort, isn't it?
努力だよね。
Exactly, Momoka's effort.
本当にそう、ももちゃんの努力。
Right.
そう。
Now everyone can see the comments, and they're all so welcoming, right?
今ならみんなウェルカムでコメント見られるじゃん。
So you can watch with peace of mind.
だから安心して見れるよね。
Yeah, really.
ね、本当に。
Because it's now,
今だから
if Momo-chan streamed by herself, the chat would be...
ももちゃんが、ももちゃんだけで配信をしたらそれはそれでチャット欄とか、
...quite different, wouldn't it?
だいぶ変わりそうじゃない?
The vibe, you know.
色がね。
Well, but there would also be fans who've been supporting her since back then,
ま、でも当時のずっと応援してくれてるファンとかもいるだろうから、
so that might not change.
そこは変わらないかもしれないけど。
Like, "I'm new," or "I just arrived."
新規ですとかって、新しく来ました。
"I came after watching the Lumina Grand Prix."
ルミナグランプリを見てきましたと。
Oh, that's nice, originally...
いいな、あの、もともと
Ah, a first-timer, huh?
あ、初見ですね。
Yeah, that happens.
あるあるある。
Oh, really.
え、本当。
Like, "Hello, first-timers!"
初見さんこんにちはとかって。
It would actually get pretty wild.
逆にこさぶっちゃう。
Ah, that's right. Like, "I came from Lumigra."
あ、そうだね、それこそルミグラから来ました。
Oh no, what if "Lumigra" gets officially adopted?
あ、どうしよう、公式にルミグラ採用されちゃったらどうしよう。
Just kidding.
嘘です。
I'm just saying it.
私が言ってるだけです。
Right.
はい。
Anyway, I've also done a general review, so for now,
そんなこんなでちょっと私も、あの、全体の振り返りもしたので1回
right, let's set Episode 8 aside for a moment. What I want to see here is...
そうね、8話は置いといて、1回ここで私が見たい
I've picked out a scene I personally want to talk about, and as you might have guessed, it's Episode 6.
個人的に語りたいシーンピックアップしましたのでえ、お察しの通り6話です。
Please take a look.
見てください。
Go ahead.
どうぞ。
Okay.
はい。
Well, I also considered Episode 8, but if I watched Episode 8, I'd just burst into tears.
いや、8話とも悩んだんですけど、8話見ると私が号泣してしまうので
My current prediction for Rewrite's ranking is Hiiragi-san...
現時点でのリライトの順位予想は柊さん
5th place, or 5th place.
5位または5位。
They're right on the border of whether they can advance to the main competition.
ちょうど本戦に進めるかどうかのボーダー上にいる。
That's right.
そうなんですよ。
That's a good rank.
いい順位だ。
Isn't it great that you can say, "that's a good rank"?
いい順位だって出せるのめちゃくちゃ良くない?
This event hasn't fully taken shape yet.
今回のイベントはまだ完全には形になっていない。
It's not in.
入らないんだよ。
It's not in yet, but isn't it great that you can already say, "that's a good rank"?
入ってなくてそろそろそれでいい順位だって言えるの良くない?
Oh, here it comes.
あ、来ました。
Kiriya.
霧谷
Mm-hm.
うん。
Sensei, it's been a while.
先生自分お久しぶりです。
I crossed my arms without realizing it.
いつの間にか腕組んでたな。
Yeah.
そうだな。
I get nervous.
緊張するんだよな。
When I just look at Hiiragi-san.
普通に柊さんを見ると。
But this time...
しかし今回は
It doesn't seem like we just ran into each other by chance.
偶然鉢合わせたというわけではなさそうだな。
Too mature.
大人すぎる。
Yes.
はい。
That's right.
そうです。
I heard from Tsubaki-san and the others that Hiiragi-san would be here today.
椿さん達に柊さんは今日ここにいると聞いたので。
They're too nice.
いい人達すぎる。
What do you want?
何の用?
I came to ask a favor.
お願いをしに来ました。
You're so cool, Haruka.
かっこいいよ、はるか。
A favor?
お願い?
You're right.
そうですよね。
It's surprising, isn't it?
びっくりですよね。
I was surprised too.
私もびっくりしました。
Hiiragi-san,
柊さん
could you please give us some advice
どうかアドバイスをいただけませんか?
for our event during this Lumina Time?
今回のルミナタイムで開催する私達のイベントに
This time, it was supposed to be a project you all came up with yourselves, wasn't it?
今回はお前達自身が考える企画だっただろう。
You're absolutely right.
おっしゃる通り。
The rules stated that we should think of everything, including the setlist and staging.
このルールにはセトリや演出は考えるって全てが考えるようにとありました。
However, there's no problem asking for advice on the overall concept and production policy.
ですが全体のコンセプトやプロデュース方針についてアドバイスを仰ぐことは問題ありません。
She got ahead of them.
先手を打った。
I also confirmed with management.
運営にも確認しました。
So it's fine.
だから大丈夫です。
You're sure?
確信?
But in this Grand Prix, you all are Rewrite's rivals, aren't you?
だがこのグランプリにおいてお前達はリライトのライバルだろう。
Why ask me?
なぜ私に聞く?
You already know the answer to that, don't you?
って聞いといて分かってんでしょ。
It's because I believe there's no other producer who has aimed to deliver hope and actually done so more than Hiiragi-san.
柊さん以上に希望を届けることを目指し、実行してきたプロデューサーはいないと思っているからです。
Can I put it into words? Besides, we and Rewrite are on the same team now.
言葉にできるのそれに私達とリライトは今同じチーム。
This outcome will affect Rewrite as well.
今回の結果はリライトにも影響します。
Rewrite's predicted rank is currently 5th.
リライトの予想順位は現在5位だ。
There's a high chance they'll win even without my help.
私が手を差し伸べなくても勝ち残る可能性は高い。
But from here, from here...
ここから、ここから。
Even so, it's not 100%.
だとしてでも100%ではありません。
Then there's still a chance they could lose.
なら敗退する可能性だってあります。
I want to increase their chances of winning even more.
勝ち抜く角度をもっと上げたい。
Don't you agree?
そうは思いませんか?
Can high schoolers use 'angle' like that?
高校生が角度って使えるの?
I can't, even now.
私は無理です、今でも。
There it is.
来た。
So cool.
かっこいい。
So please, I'm begging you.
だからどうかお願いします。
Hiiragi-san.
柊さん。
To win,
勝ち抜くため
and to deliver hope,
希望を届けるために
please give us your advice.
アドバイスをください。
They specifically chose the words 'to deliver hope' here, didn't they?
ここでわざわざ希望を届けるためにって言葉選んでんだもんな。
So cool.
かっこいいよ。
What do you want to know?
何が聞きたい?
Right now, we're struggling because we don't have a clear criterion for how to narrow down the ideas we've come up with.
今は出てきたアイデアをどう絞るべきかその判断軸がないため悩んでいます。
Please take a look at this.
こちらを見てください。
Oh, let me see that document.
あ、その資料見せて。
It's a list of the event ideas we have right now.
今出ているイベントのアイデアの一覧です。
Wow, you're so well-prepared.
すごいよな、用意周到。
Yes, we are.
はいです。
I think all the ideas themselves are good.
自体はどれもいいものだと思うんです。
But how should we put them together for the event?
ですがこれをイベントに向けてどうまとめていけばいいのか。
It's about whether we can create a path.
道を作れるかどうかだ。
A path?
道?
That's right.
そうだ。
In other words,
つまり
it's about whether we can create a path that makes those who find it difficult to look forward believe in a story of hope again.
前を向くことが難しいものに再び希望の物語を信じさせる道が作れているかどうか。
That will be our criterion.
それが判断軸になる。
A story of hope...
希望の物語
That's what I thought it meant.
それはつまり来たと思った。
I couldn't breathe just now.
呼吸できなかった、今。
Huh, we're back, aren't we?
え、戻ってきましたね。
Advice from Hiiragi-san?
柊さんにアドバイスを?
They gave it to you, right?
くれたんだよね。
I was really surprised by this.
私これびっくりしたもん。
I never thought...
まさか
you'd go talk to a producer from another group. I'm surprised.
他のグループのプロデューサーに話を聞きに行くとはびっくり。
As far as I know, they're the person who can view these kinds of events most objectively, so I thought they'd surely give us good ideas.
私が知る限りこういうイベントを1番俯瞰して見れる人だからきっといいアイデアをくれると思って。
You really see them as a person, don't you?
ちゃんと人間として見れてんだな。
When we were first asked for Hiiragi-san's schedule, we were surprised too.
最初に柊さんの予定を教えてほしいと言われた時は、私達も驚きました。
Sorry for making such a difficult request.
無理を言ってごめんね。
I wanted to sort things out in my head, so I wanted to talk to you directly.
自分の中で整理したかったから、直接話しておきたかったんだ。
It's no problem.
構いません。
Hiiragi-san is someone we can rely on, after all.
柊さんは頼れる人ですからね。
Thank you.
ありがとう。
So, the advice I got from Hiiragi-san was that it's good
それで柊さんにもらったアドバイスを
to build the entire event with rivals and become a bit more open,
ライバル達とイベント全体を組み立ててあと1つ打ち解けてるのがいいん
right?
ですね。
Could you take a look?
見てもらっていいかな?
Of course.
もちろんです。
I'll send it over.
配信します。
Knowing what happens next, this certainly seems like it could work.
その後のことを知ってると確かにこれならいけそうね。
Even Hikari-san,
ひかりさんでも
this won't make for good streaming content, will it?
これじゃあ配信映えはしないんじゃない?
That's
その
right.
通り。
You know, I really wanted to know more about Hikari.
ね、もっとひかりのこと色々知りたかったなっていう風に思いました。
I really want them to perform together again, don't you?
ね、また共演して欲しいですよね。
I'm super curious about what kind of songs Hikarin actually sings.
実際にひかりんがどういう曲歌ってるのかとかめちゃくちゃ気になるし。
She's cute, isn't she?
可愛いよね。
Um, after this, we'll see the card illustration.
あの、この後あの、カードイラスト見ますけど。
Airi, I think?
愛理かな。
She's in Airi's card, you know.
愛理のカードにちょっといるんだよね。
Yeah, I know.
そう、分かる。
It's tough when you create too many characters, you know.
キャラ作りすぎると大変なんだよね。
It's tough to create a persona.
キャラ作ると大変なんだよ。
And there will definitely come a moment when you have to overcome that.
それを乗り越えなきゃいけない瞬間が絶対に来るんだよ。
I get it.
分かる。
But Hikarin is who she is now because she overcame that.
でもそれを乗り越えて今のひかりんがあるから。
I hope Hikarin keeps doing her best.
頑張って欲しいね、ひかりんにも。
And what will happen in the finals from now on?
そしてこの先決勝戦どんなことがあるのか。
It's finally the finals, but it's still like the preliminaries, you know.
ね、いよいよの決勝ですけど、まだだから予選だからね。
The real show is yet to come.
これから本番ですから。
What kind of sights will we see with the remaining four groups?
残り4組でどんな景色が見られるのか。
I'm really looking forward to it.
とても楽しみでございます。
Well then, shall we take a look at the card illustrations?
そんなこんなでカードイラスト見ていきますか。
Yes.
はい。
Alright, excuse me, first up is Haruka-sensei.
じゃ、すいません、まず遥先生。
Haruka-sensei.
遥先生。
Yes, here it is.
はい、こちらです。
Yeah, this one was cool too.
はい、これもかっこよかったね。
When the banner was announced, I felt a shiver down my spine, thinking, 'Oh, she still has this cool side to her, doesn't she?'
いや、バナー発表された時のあ、なんか背筋伸びるわっていうのとこういうかっこいいもまだそうだね。
I couldn't help but grin, thinking, 'Yeah, she's got it.'
ね、あるよねってニヤニヤしちゃった。
It's great.
いいですよ。
Thank you very much.
本当にありがとうございます。
And then there's this!
で、これですよ、ひ。
Huh? This, um, I wonder if everyone knows about this.
えこのさうん、みんな分かんないね。
These gloves, you know, the ones that don't cover the whole area.
このさあの、手袋のさ、全部ないやつ、面積。
Gloves with no surface area at all.
全部面積ない手袋。
What do you call them?
なんて言うの。
This definitely suits Haruka-san, doesn't it?
これがさ絶対似合うんですよね、遥さんってね。
It's great, isn't it?
いいですよね。
And, well, we'll definitely talk about the costume details later.
で、あの、細かいところもちょっと後で衣装の話は絶対にしようね。
Let's look at this.
これ見ようか。
Alright.
よし。
Well, if we don't keep going, we won't make any progress.
じゃ、どんどん行かないと、全然進まないから。
So, here it is.
ではい、これです。
This is what I was just talking about.
これ、さっき言ってたやつ。
Hikarin and Airi at the cram school.
学習塾のひかりんと愛理。
These two were great too.
この2人も良かったな。
They feel like the variety show duo.
なんかバラエティ組って感じ。
You really get the sense that the atmosphere changes from here, don't you?
ここからなんか空気が変わる感じがすごいしますよね。
They're so cute. Their height...
可愛いんだよな、なんか身長
...and you know, I only realized Hikari was surprisingly short when her full-body illustration came out.
的にもさ、ひかり意外とちっちゃいんだっていうの立ち絵出て初めて知ったけど、
So cute.
可愛い。
Airi's great too.
愛理もいいよ。
Right?
ね。
And then, it's beautiful, isn't it?
からのね、綺麗ですね。
This one, you know.
これはね。
Like this, maybe?
こうかな。
So, everyone, try looking at it vertically.
で、縦にしてみて、みんな。
It's really good.
めっちゃいいから。
Wow, the lighting is beautiful.
うわあ、ライティング綺麗。
That feeling of light shining from behind, right?
この後ろからさ、光差してる感じがさね。
So detailed.
こまけえ。
Seriously, when I do this... wait, has it just been the back of my head showing this whole time?
本当にこうやってやるとてか私のずっと後頭部しか映ってないこれ、今。
Just a moment.
ちょっとお待ちになって。
Ah, Ren-kun.
ああ、廉くん。
This was really good.
これめっちゃ良かった。
Oh, and the notebook is subtly a penguin.
あ、地味にノートをペンギンだし。
Cute.
可愛い。
Oh, Haruka's penguin... her love for penguins shows up even in places like this.
あ、遥のペンギンが、ペンギン好きのこんなところにも出てる。
Oh, wait, there's a penguin in the stationery too!
あ、待って、文房具のところにもペンギンいんじゃん。
Right, um, Ren-kun's standing illustration right now... is it what you'd call his old outfit? I'm not sure.
そう、あの、廉くんの立ち絵って今、あの、旧衣装って言うのかな、分かんない。
Since it's his outfit from the beginning, it's nice to see him in these kinds of illustrations now, isn't it?
あの、初期からの衣装の方だから、こういうイラストのところで今の見れるのいいよね。
And he's cool.
で、かっこいいです。
Beautiful.
綺麗。
Nice.
いい。
Ah, well, this is something I can't quite look at directly.
あ、ま、ちょっと直視できないやつですね、これ。
Hee.
ひ。
Next.
次。
Ah, this was good, good... Seriously, is this really a 3-star?
ああ、これはよかっ、よかってこれさ、本当に星3?
Really a 3-star?
本当に星3?
Ah, it's cute.
ああ、可愛いです。
It's beautiful.
綺麗です。
Truly beautiful today as well.
本当に今日も美しいでございます。
It's wonderful, isn't it?
素晴らしいですね。
Thank you as always.
いつもありがとうございます。
And this is it.
で、これです。
Right?
ね。
Is this really a 3-star?
本当に星3?
Is it really a 3-star?
分かんないよね、もう基準がね。
I don't even know the standards anymore.
はい、みのりちゃんですよ。
Yes, it's Minori-chan.
みのりちゃんです。
It's Minori-chan.
あ、綺麗ですね。
Oh, it's beautiful.
なんか全体的に今回あの、イラストが全体的にあの、
Somehow, this time, the illustrations overall have a beautiful black tone,
夜空というか綺麗なブラック調なので、ここではっきり造形
like a night sky. So here, we can clearly see the details
とか見れるよね、衣装のね。
of the costume, right?
裏地緑なんだね。
The lining is green, isn't it?
ももジャンカラーかな。
I guess it's the Momojan color.
いいね。
Nice.
綺麗だよ。
It's beautiful.
みのり綺麗だよ。
Minori, you're beautiful.
さ、ということで全部見ました。
Alright, so we've seen all of them.
え、今回イラスト制作チームから今回の衣装についてのコメントをいただいております。
Uh, this time we've received comments about these costumes from the illustration production team.
読んでいきたいと思います。
I'd like to read them now.
今回はアウェイな場所で複数のアイドルと合同ライブをするという課題に向き合い、
This time, facing the challenge of performing a joint live show with multiple idols in an unfamiliar place,
成功へ導くために遥が活躍
Haruka plays an active role in leading it to success.
するストーリーとなります。
That's the story.
ストーリーの合同ライブという点などから着想を得て見せたいものを絞り、
Drawing inspiration from elements like the joint live show in the story, we narrowed down what we wanted to showcase,
真っ黒な夜空の中、ひときわ輝くもも
In the pitch-black night sky, we aimed to express a particularly shining
ジャンを表現しようと考えました。
Momojan.
そのため今回はあえて黒地の布と目を引く星飾りを使ったシンプルな組み合わせのデザインとし、
Therefore, this time, we intentionally went with a simple combination design using black fabric and eye-catching star decorations,
レオニとはまた
And unlike Leoni,
違っは夜空で輝く星をテーマとしたデザインとなっております。
It's a design themed around stars shining in the night sky.
89割黒い布想定でデザインしておりますので、
Since it's designed with 80-90% black fabric in mind,
チープになりすぎないよう、ベルベットやサテン系の質感で高級
to avoid looking too cheap, we're using velvet and satin-like textures
感ある光沢を出し、一部こまやか
to give it a luxurious sheen, along with some intricate details.
な衣装でももジャンとしてのも新しい印象の大人っぽいアイドル衣装になるよう
This way, even with a detailed costume, it becomes a mature idol outfit
にしています。
that gives Momojan a fresh impression.
うん、本当にそう。
Yeah, that's really true.
ベルベットって分かる?
You know velvet, right?
あの、いい絨毯です。
It's like a really nice carpet.
いい絨毯の、あの、触ってみたくなるいい絨毯です。
A really nice carpet that makes you want to touch it.
あれって、あの、アイドル衣装の冬系衣装によく使われる生地なんですけど、
That fabric is often used for winter-style idol costumes,
まさにこの12月とかの季節めちゃくちゃ
and it's absolutely perfect for a season like December.
いいんですよ。
The luster and luxurious feel when it hits the light.
ライトに当たった時の光沢感、高級感。
Satin is the same.
サテンもそう。
Satin shines really nicely when it catches the light,
サテンの方がその光とかに当たった時にいい感じにね、
but velvet also has a surprisingly dignified feel,
輝いてくれるんですけど、ベルベットも意外とね、重厚
absorbing and reflecting light beautifully.
感があってで、ライトもいい感じに吸収して反射してくれてっていうなってね。
Isn't it amazing how they illustrate the fabric so well?
めちゃくちゃ生地をイラストで書くってすごくない?
Right?
ね。
This is it.
ここですよ。
This is the attention to detail in Momojan's costumes.
ももジャン衣装のこだわりここですよ。
It's wonderful.
素晴らしいです。
Right?
ね。
Oh, time's already up.
あれ、もう時間過ぎてた。
Can you watch it?
見れますか?
Yeah, this one makes me cry too.
ええ、これも泣いちゃうんだよ。
We'll be watching the 3DMV, though.
3DMV見ますけどね。
Rather than just listening to the song on its own, please watch it with the 3DMV.
あの曲単体で聞くより3DMVで見てください。
Absolutely.
絶対。
Well, we're about to watch it now, but...
いや、これから見るんですけど。
So, next,
ということで、続いては今回
we'll watch the 3DMV that Karasuya-sabou-san commissioned for this event, and then
のイベントのためにカラスヤサボウさんに書き下ろしいただいた3DMVを見て楽曲
we'll talk about the song.
についての話をしていこうと思います。
First, please watch the 3DMV.
それではまず、3DMVご覧ください。
Here you go.
どうぞ。
Look, the scenery always covered in...
ほらさいつもまみれた景色
...under a sky that saw it. A voyage continued aimlessly, swept along, always making mistakes, nothing ever disappearing.
を見た空にあてもないまま続いた航海流されるままでいつだって間違って何だって消え
I felt like I was humming that nostalgic song.
なくて口ずさんでた気がしの懐かしい歌。
Look, look, watch me!
ほらさほらさ私を見ていて
Keep shining so I don't get lost anymore. Look, watch me, keep shining so I don't get lost anymore.
もう迷わないように輝き続けてほらさ私を見ていてもう迷わないように輝き続けていい。
Okay.
はい。
And that was "Horasa."
ということでほらさでした。
It's good.
いい。
It's all good.
全部いい。
Um, oh, wait, you know, the way each person's expression becomes visible here.
あの、ああ、ちょ、待って、えっとね、ここのここの1人ずつ表情が見えていく感じ。
On the side of the stage, you know, fans can definitely only see it from above the stage, but...
ステージの横のね、絶対ファンの人達はステージの上からでしか見れないけど、
this part behind the scenes, what we're about to see now...
この裏側のここ今からのところ
...these expressions.
を、この表情。
Right.
ね。
This part.
ここ。
Everyone definitely says it here, right?
ここ絶対みんな言うでしょ。
It's the part where everyone says "yeah?" together.
ね、みんなで言ってねのところだもん。
That's what it is, right?
そういうことだもんね。
Oh, yeah, exactly.
ああ、ね、そう、そういうこと。
This part is great.
ここいいんですよ。
You know, the music video's quality is so good, it's elevated. Ah, this part.
あのね、ミュージックビデオのクオリティが良くてね、上がっててあ、ここ。
Uh, wait a moment.
え、ちょっと待ってね。
Um, you know, this part, where they're all in sync, it's beautiful.
えっとね、ここのそう、あの、揃ったふうに綺麗ですよ。
Oh, this is nice.
ああ、これいいですね。
Right.
ね。
You know, this part here, this is also good.
あのね、ここの、ここもいいですね。
And wow, this background design, they're singing with all their might, it's really good.
でいや、この背景めちゃくちゃデザイン、デザイン、全力で歌ってすごくいいんです。
It's wonderful.
素敵なんです。
And this, wow, beautiful, the stars.
で、この、うわ、綺麗、星。
Right.
ね。
It's so good.
めっちゃいいよ。
After this, here, this part.
この後ここ、ここ。
Here.
ここ。
Right.
ね。
Then after this, the formation change, yes.
この後のフォーメーション変えての、そう。
Each person's expression, this, the stairs, right, right.
1人ずつの表情、これ、階段ね、ね。
This part.
ここ。
So, look closely.
で、よく見て。
Each one, little by little, you know... this part, it's one whole with everyone. It's wonderful.
1人ずつちょっとずつ、ね、ここがね、これ全員で1つ、はい、素晴らしい。
This is just great, you know.
これがいいんですよ、もう。
Honestly, when I first saw this, I was like, 'Whoa, what is this?'
本当に、これ初めて見た時にさ、うわ、何これと思って。
Yeah.
うん。
But
だけど
he can deliver hope.
彼なら希望を届けられる。
I think so.
私はそう思う。
If Haruka thinks so...
遥がそう思うなら。
I
私は
want to go with this plan.
この案でいきたいです。
Right, so Rewrite is what's going to back this up, you know?
そう、これを後押ししてくれるのがリライトっていう意味ね。
Of course, yes.
もちろんはい。
I do think it's best to consider the worries and the impact on voting as much as possible.
心配や投票への影響も最大限考えた方がいいとは思います。
I think the members will say it's fine, of course.
メンバーがそれでいいと思うがもちろん言ってくれると思うんだけど。
Because what we should do as idols is, more than anything, deliver hope to the people right in front of us.
アイドルとしてすべきことは何より1番目の前の人に希望を届けることだと思うので。
Rewrite, who we'd see as rivals, in the sense that our concepts overlap.
ライバル視するであろうリライト、コンセプトかぶってるしっていう意味で。
And what's more, they went to ask Hiiragi-san without permission, right?
しかも柊さんに勝手に聞きに行かれてるわけなんだよね。
Well, not exactly without permission.
勝手にじゃないけど。
In that sense, we'd naturally go with Haruka's plan.
そういう意味で言うと私たちは当然遥の案に乗るわ。
Even though I think it can't be helped, for Rewrite to properly say that's good there...
しょうがないと思うのに、そこでちゃんとリライトにそれがいいって言ってくれるのは
It's good to see that they're willing to cooperate with the same feelings, even though they're rivals.
ちゃんと同じ気持ちで上で協力しよう、ライバルだけどっていうのが見えていいよね。
Because we absolutely want to deliver hope to those kids.
あの子達に絶対に希望を届けたいから。
That's the idea.
っていう
But this idea also has the possibility of leaving our fans watching the stream behind.
でもこのアイデアは配信を見てる私たちのファンが置き去りになる可能性もある。
She knows that.
それは分かってるの。
Arima-san is amazing; her perspective is so human, and I like that.
すごい有馬さんがだから有馬さんに視点がめっちゃ人間味あっていいね。
Our fans,
私たちのファンは
I think, believe we'll give our all to those girls here.
ここであの子達に全力で向かうって信じてると思うんだ。
Yes, Arima-san is such a good person, she even thinks of all the fans.
そう、ファン、ファンの皆さんのことも考えられるいい子です、有馬さん。
That's what I want to say, but we also
って言いたいところだけど私たちだって
don't want to be a team that can't deliver hope.
希望を届けられないチームではいたくない。
Ah, then,
あ、じゃあ
since Arima-san is involved, she'll do it seriously.
有馬さんがからには本気でやるから。
I wonder if she's finally showing us her true self.
ちゃんと見せてくれるようになったのかな。
Thank you.
ありがとう。
I don't know though.
分かんないけど。
Well then, everyone.
それじゃあみんな。
It's strange, I've been calling her Arima, Arima this whole time, but I'm actually calling her Hiiragi-san.
私今自分でずっと有馬有馬って呼んでたからおかしいな、柊さんって呼んでるからだ。
Yes, so, you've just watched Episode 6.
はい、ということでえ、6話を見ていただきましたけれども。
Right, yes.
ね、はい。
Um, I've been saying this even before we started, before watching this, but the conversation between Hiiragi-san and Haruka, you know,
あの、私はもう始まるま、これ見る前から言ってましたけど柊さんと遥の会話やっぱあの、
the strength to go and negotiate directly one-on-one
直談判を1対1でし
is truly wonderful,
に行くというその強さが本当に素晴らしくて、
And what's more, knowing that they confronted each other during Haruka's previous event, to go again
しかも前の遥のバナーの時に対峙してるのを分かった上でもう1
to meet Hiiragi-san, what she's carrying is a bit different from back then.
は、柊さんに会いに行くというのはちょっとやっぱ抱えてるものが当時とは違う。
That, you know, I thought was really cool,
それね、やっぱかっこいいなと思いましたし、
Actually, this confrontation scene, we shot it twice,
実際この対峙してるシーンはあの2回撮ったんですけど、
probably two takes.
多分2
The second take was used, but when I did the first one,
回目の分が使われてるんですけど、1回目通した時に
Haruka still had this feeling towards Hiiragi-san, this...
やっぱどうしてもその遥が柊さんに対して持ってるそのお、
...slight anxiety towards adults,
対大人に対する若干のその不安とか、
like, 'What should I do now?'
え、これから
She didn't know what to do, so she honestly went to ask for advice.
どうしたらいいか分かんないから素直にアドバイスを求めに行くみたいなの
She was a bit hesitant at that point.
ところで若干揺れてたりとかしてた
But it wasn't like that; here,
んですけどそうじゃなくてここは
they wanted me to play it as Haruka challenging him.
遥として吹っ掛けてくださいってあったんです。
Yes, to Hiiragi-san. I was going to him for advice,
柊さんにそう、もうアドバイスを聞きに行くためにとりあえず彼にい、
but I was given the direction to challenge him, saying,
でも角度欲しいですよね。
'You need an angle, right? To definitely get past this point,
確実に
why don't you cooperate?'
ここを通過するためには協力しませんか、吹っ掛けてくださいっていうディレクションをいただいて、
What? That sounds so
何それめっちゃ
interesting! I want to do that!
面白そう、やりたいって
And that's what I did in the second take, the one you just heard.
で、やったのが2回目だった、今のだったんですけど。
Of course, I believe that Haruka's position as a producer
あのもちろんね、あの、1人のプロデューサーとしての立ち位置がやっぱ遥の中で
is gradually being established within her,
ちょっとずつ確立されていっ
and that's one of the core themes of this story.
てるんだなっていうのが今回のストーリーの1個の軸だと私は思ってるので
I hope that was clearly conveyed in the scene with Hiiragi-san.
それがこの柊さんとのシーンで明確に出てたらいいなという風に思っております。
Eventually, even the sound director,
そのうちあの
who gives me directions, has been creating Haruka's character with me,
音響監督さんディレクションしてくださる方もだんだんその遥のことをやっぱ一緒に作ってきてるんで
so I'm really happy to hear them gradually suggest things like,
そろそろ
'Haruka can show a bit more of herself here,
遥ここでちょっと出しても
don't you think?'
いいんじゃないですかとかっていうのがちょっとずつ聞けてすごく嬉しいんですよね。
Especially in Episode 6, that really comes through.
今回特にその6話ではそれが特に出てるので、
That's a part I really wanted all of you to see.
皆さんに是非観て欲しかったなというところでした。
Right.
はい。
I guess that's about it.
そんな感じかな。
Oh!
あ
My earring fell off.
イヤリングが落ちた。
Just a moment.
ちょっと待ってね。
Anyway,
ということで
Okay, we'll pause the Episode 6 recap here and move on to the card illustrations, I think.
はい、一旦6話の振り返りはここまでにしてカードイラストかな。
Oh, is that alright?
あ、いいですか。
Episode 8.
8話
Seriously,
やっぱ
First of all, congratulations on advancing, Momojan!
まずとりあえず進出おめでとう、ももジャン。
Seriously, congratulations!
本当におめでとう。
It's great.
いいんです。
It's fine, I just thought it'd be good if they could make it to the finals.
大丈夫、もうとりあえず決勝に上がれればいいと思ってたの。
But they got second place!
でも2位だよ。
That's a huge leap forward!
すごい大躍進ですよ。
Right? Chi-A was first, and Momojan was second.
ね、1位がChi-Aで、2位がももジャン。
When there were only two groups left, Haruka's feeling of 'we can't give up here yet'...
残り2組になった時のあの、まだまだここで諦めちゃいけないっていう遥のあの気持ち。
Ah, I'm about to cry.
あ、泣きそう。
That scene was so cool.
あのシーンめっちゃかっこよかったな。
When the other members were thinking, 'Ah, it might be over,' Haruka was like...
他のメンバーがああ、もうダメかもってなってる時に遥がさ
...I'm about to cry.
泣きそう。
That scene, it was really good, and it conveyed that you can't give up yet.
あれね、本当に良くて、まだ諦めちゃいけないって。
And then, Haruka, representing everyone, says 'Thank you' first.
で、代表して遥がありがとうございますって最初に言うわけですよ。
That 'Thank you' was truly a tear-jerker.
あの、ありがとうございますはもうマジ泣きでした。
Of course, it's Haruka.
もちろん遥ですよ。
She's saying it as Haruka, but I was just so happy about everything, truly happy.
遥として言ってますけど、なんかもう全部嬉しくて、本当に嬉しくて。
Right.
ね。
But, that 'Thank you,' you know.
でも、あの、ありがとうございますね。
Somehow,
なんか
I think we recorded that part twice at first.
最初あれ、2回撮った気がする。
The first time, I was trying to do it with the feeling of needing to be really solid,
1回目は本当しっかりしなきゃっていう気持ちでやってたんですけど、
but they said, 'No, I think you can show more emotion.'
いや、もっと感情出していいと思います。
Because this is a turning point, and I thought, 'That's true.'
ここで1個の区切りになるんで、確かにって。
When I read it again, it was just too good.
もう1回読んだらもうあまりに良くて。
And I thought, 'Can I really cry a second time?'
2回目でも泣けんのかよと思って。
Yeah, I ended up giving my full-power 'Thank you.'
はい、全力のありがとうございますとか出ましたけどね。
And then, right, Hikarin,
で、もうそう、ひかりんが
this time in the qualifiers, she was a respectable 5th, but since only four groups could advance, Hikarin,
今回予選ね、堂々5位ですけど、今回4組しか上がれないってことでひかりんがねあの、
said that her dream
ここでひかりんの夢は
would end here for now, but that
ここで1回終わるけど、みたいな。
everyone else would surely continue to shine.
他みんながきっとまだまだ輝いてくれるか、みたいなこと言ってくれて。
It was a qualifying round where I was really helped by Hikarin's unique way of speaking,
もうなんかひかりん節にいっぱい助けられてた予選だったので、
especially Minori, you know.
まあ、みのりも特にね。
So, including that bond, it's really sad that Hikarin won't be there anymore,
なので、そこの絆も含めてなんかな、ひかりんがいなくなっちゃうの本当寂しいけど、
but because we connect everyone's will
こうやってみんなの意思
that's what makes us a team.
を繋いでいくからこそチームっていう
I really felt that the final match of those preliminaries would resonate deeply.
その予選の最終戦がめちゃくちゃ響いてくるんだろうなっていうのすごく感じて。
Also, personally, when Hikarin's
あと私個人的にひかりんの
visual design was added,
あの、ビジュアルが
I was incredibly happy.
追加された時にめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったんですよね。
I was so curious about her, wondering what kind of girl she was,
めちゃくちゃ気になってたから、どういう子かなとか、
and I had imagined her from the feel of her voice, but
あの、ボイスの感じからイメージをしてたんですけど、
she's super cute!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いやん。
It was packed with so much.
モリモリ盛りだくさんで。